GABRIELA SWANK

San Diego, CA | gabrielaswank@icloud.com | (719) 231-0540

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Versatile and determined individual with a proven background in customer due diligence, fraud investigation, transaction monitoring and banking operations. Experienced in managing real-time queues and identifying high-risk transactions with a strong attention to detail. Goal oriented, continuously meets deadlines and has a motivated desire to learn and improve.

SKILLS

- Fraud Detection and Prevention
- Investigation and Analysis
- Transaction Monitoring
- Languages: English and Portuguese
- Customer Due Diligence
- Knowledge of BSA/AML Regulations
- JackHenry, Tableau, ChexSystems, Lexis Nexis, Clear, SalesForce

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Senior Operations Specialist | LPL Financial - San Diego

June 2023 - Current

- Identifies inefficiencies in existing processes and procedures, leading to the implementation of strategic updates to streamline operations.
- Executes SQL queries to generate reports and perform data validation.
- Monitors and addresses investment accounts falling below program funding requirements.
- Collaborates with internal departments for seamless processing of journals, distributions, and conversions.

Senior Fraud Specialist | Axos Bank - San Diego

December 2022 - June 2023

- Observed customer transactions to detect fraudulent activities such as account takeover, identity theft, and consumer fraud.
- Managed real time queue such as ACH transfers, check deposits, and document verification to identify high risk transactions for personal and business accounts.
- Reviewed and investigated potential fraud cases and alerts to mitigate loss.
- Escalate suspicious activity by submitting Questionable Activity Report.

Senior Processing Specialist | Axos Bank - San Diego

September 2021 – December 2022

- Conducted thorough due diligence on new business account applications, assessing risk and ensuring compliance with AML/BSA regulations.
- Reviews OFAC alerts and hits on screening system and ensure they are cleared appropriately.
- Conducted negative news search on new accounts applications utilizing Lexis Nexis/Clear and other thirdparty internet related searches and document evidence appropriately.
- Assisted customers with ACH transfers, wires, deposits, and questions regarding online banking.

EDUCATION

Sacramento City College - Sacramento, CA

July 2022 - December 2024

Associate of Science in Cybersecurity and Information Assurance

- Phi Theta Kappa Honor Society
- President's Honor Roll